Guide to the Oscar I. Norwich Collection of Maps of Africa and Its Islands, 1486 - ca. 1865 NORWICH
David Rumsey Map Center
- Africa divided according to the extent of its Principall Parts in which are distinquished one from the other Empires, Monarchies, Kingdoms, States and Peoples which at this time inhabite Africa. -- London: Berry, William, fl. 1669-1708; Berry, William, fl. 1669-1708, 1680; NOR 0047; : Colored; 54 
  Norwich number: 0047
  RID: MOA 0068
- L'Afrique divisee suivant l'estendue de ses principales parties, ou sont distinque's les uns des autres, les Empires, Monarchies, Royaumes, Estats et Peuples qui partagent aujourd'hui L'Afrique sur les relations les plus nouvelles ... = Africa divided into parts which are further divided into empires etc. -- Amsterdam: Valck, G. (Gerard), 1651 or 2-1726.; Valck, G. (Gerard), 1651 or 2-1726., 1680; NOR 0049; : Colored; 46 cm. x 57 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: A lion, elephant, leopard, camel and crocodile surround the scales which are in Italian, French and Spanish. Title across top, also appeared in Jaillot's map (see NOR 0046). L'Afrique distinguee en ses principales parties scavoir la Barbarie, le Biledulgerid, L'Egypte, le Saara ou le Desert, le Pays des Negres, la Guinee, La Nubie, L'Abissinie, le Zanguebar; le Congo, le Monomotapa, Les Cafres, Les Isles de Canaries, du Cap-Verd, de S. Thomas, L'sle Dauphine autrement Madagascar ...
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0049, p. 60
  Norwich number: 0049
  RID: MOA 0070
- Africae Accurata Tabula. = Detailed map of Africa. -- Amsterdam: De Ram, Joan (Johannes) 1648-1693; De Ram, Joan (Johannes) 1648-1693, 1680-1690; NOR 0050; : Colored; 44 cm. x 56 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Similar to Danckerts' map (see NOR 0057); Prime meridian through Tenerif.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0050, p. 62
  Norwich number: 0050
  RID: MOA 0071
- Route maritime de Brest a Siam, et de Siam a Brest, faite en 1685 et 1686 selon les remarques des six Peres Jesuites, envoiez par le Roy de France en qualite de ses Mathematiciens dans les Indes, et la Chine. Dresse par le Pere Coronelli ... = Sea route from Brest to Siam and back taken by the six Jesuit fathers in 1685 and 1686 ... -- Paris: J. B. Nolin; Coronelli, Vincenzo, 1650-1718; Coronelli, Vincenzo, 1650-1718 Exploration, 1687; NOR 0051; : Uncolored; 44 cm. x 73 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Folio map extends eastward to include the Middle and Far East. Map traces the sea routes of Jesuit Fathers. Inset: Elevation of Table Mountain, Plan of Table Bay, Plans of Siam, Louvo and Batavia; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0051, p. 63
  Norwich number: 0051
  RID: MOA 0072
- Africa. -- Venice: Coronelli, Vincenzo, 1650-1718; Coronelli, Vincenzo, 1650-1718, 1688; NOR 0052; : Uncolored; 91 cm. x 75 cm.
  Source: Atlante Veneto
  Descriptive Notes: Six gores assembled to form one map. One of the most detailed of early maps of Africa. Coronelli stated "besides outlining the Monomotapa and Abyssinia Countries we have been the first to describe correctly the source of Nile River, correcting by many degrees the errors of the Ancients." (E.L. Stevenson, Terrestrial and Celetial Globes, vol. 2, p. 102).
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0052, p. 64
  Norwich number: 0052
  RID: MOA 0073
- Africae Accurata Tabula. = Detailed map of Africa. -- Amsterdam: Visscher, Nicolaes, 1649-1702; Visscher, Nicolaes, 1649-1702, 1690; NOR 0055; : Colored; 43 cm. x 54 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The oval cartouche is surrounded by two angels and two natives. Several ships, a whale, and flying fish are scattered throughout the seas. Dedication to D. Gerado Schaep; Prime meridian through Tenerif.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0055, p. 55
  Norwich number: 0055
  RID: MOA 0076
- L'Africa divisa neele sue Parti secondo le piu moderne, relationi colle scoperte dell'origine e corso del Nilo ... = Africa divided into its several parts according to recent information with the discoveries of the source of the Nile. -- Venice: Coronelli, Vincenzo, 1650-1718; Coronelli, Vincenzo, 1650-1718, 1691; NOR 0056; : Colored; 59 cm. x 44 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: First issued in Coronelli's atlas, Atlante Veneto. Double-sheet map includes a cartouche surrounded by various animals such as, an ostrich, crocodile, leopard, lion, camel, and an elephant. On the mainland a large piece of drapery with information about the Nile is encircled by two angels and Father Nile. Dedicated to Eccelenza del signor Gran Contestabile Colonna; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0056, p. 69
  Norwich number: 0056
  RID: MOA 0229
- Totius Africae Accuratissima Tabula. = Detailed map of the whole of Africa. -- Amsterdam: Danckerts, Justus, 1635-1701 or Danckerts, Cornelis, 1664-1717 or Danckerts, Theodore; Danckerts, Justus, 1635-1701 or Danckerts, Cornelis, 1664-1717 or Danckerts, Theodore, No date; NOR 0057; : Colored; 49 cm. x 57 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The cartouche which is identical to De Ram's map (see NOR 0050), includes people in varied costume, Moors, Africans, children and an elephant. The title appears on the masonry, with two lions; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0057, p. 71
  Norwich number: 0057
  RID: MOA 0194
- Africae tabula. = Map of Africa. -- Unknown: Anonymous, No date; NOR 0058; : Colored; 27 cm. x 34 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "Below the equator, is a colour chart indicating whether areas on the map itself are Christian, Jewish, Mohammedan or heathen"; Prime meridian through Paris.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0058, p. 71
  Norwich number: 0058
  RID: MOA 0243
  Africa -- Africa -- Unknown
- L'Afrique dressee sur les observations de Ms. de l'Academie Royale des Sciences, et quelques autres, et sur les memoires les plus recens. = Africa according to the observations made by the Royal Academy of Science ... -- Paris: L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726; L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726; L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726, 1700; NOR 0059; : Colored; 45 cm. x 58 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Issued a revised edition in 1722. L'Isle was the first to give the correct longitude, 42 degrees, to the Mediterranean and the first to discard Lakes Zaire and Zaflan; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0059, p. 72
  Norwich number: 0059
  RID: MOA 0224
- A New map of Libya or old Africk showing its general divisions, most remarkable countries or people, cities, townes, rivers, mountains c. -- London: Wells, Edward, 1667-1727; Wells, Edward, 1667-1727, 1700; NOR 0060; : Colored; 37 cm. x 49 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Southern part of Africa has been left blank, stating, "Unknown to the Antients." Dedicated to William Duke of Gloucester.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0060, p. 74
  Norwich number: 0060
  RID: MOA 0200
- Accuratissima Totius Africae Tabula in Lucem producta ... = Exact map of the whole of Africa. -- Nurnberg: Sandrart, Jakob von, 1630-1708; Sandrart, Jakob von, 1630-1708; Sandrart, Jakob von, 1630-1708, 1700; NOR 0061; : Outline color; 48 cm. x 56 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Cartouche depicts an elaborate scene with nine figures, a fat-tailed sheep, a lion, snakes and a lizard. " ... relies on Ptolemy for its description of the Nile basin." Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0061, p. 75
  Norwich number: 0061
  RID: MOA 0274
- Africa ab Auctore Naturae Suis Dotibus Instructa Geographice Exhibita an MDCC. = Africa geographically represented in 1700. -- Munich: Scherer, Heinrich, 1628-1704; Scherer, Heinrich, 1628-1704; Scherer, Heinrich, 1628-1704, NOR 0062; : Uncolored; 22 cm. x 35 cm.
  Source: Atlas Novus (1710)
  Descriptive Notes: Includes Arabia, India, the Middle East, and the bulge of Brazil. Includes islands, sea monsters (one of which has a human face), and flying fish. Animals and birds of Africa featured surrounding the cartouche; This map appeared in parts variously entitled: Geographica Naturalis, Atlas Marianne (1702), Geographica Politica, Geographica Artificalis, Tabellae Geographicae (1703), Critica Quadruportita (1710).
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0062, p. 76
  Norwich number: 0062
  RID: MOA 0028
- Africae. -- Antwerp: Fernandez de Medrano, Sebastian, 1646-1705; Fernandez de Medrano, Sebastian, 1646-1705; Fernandez de Medrano, Sebastian, 1646-1705, 1709; NOR 0065; : Uncolored; 15 cm x 18 cm.
  Source: Geographia O Moderno Descripcion Del Mundo ... (1709)
  Descriptive Notes: A group of native Africans and Moors are illustrated. Several fictitious cities are named.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0065, p. 79
  Norwich number: 0065
  RID: MOA 0029
  Africa -- Africa -- 18th c.
- To the Rt. Honourable Charles Earl of Peterborow and Monmouth. This Map of Africa. According to ye newest and most exact observations is most humbly dedicated ... -- London Moll, Herman, d. 1732, 1710; NOR 0067; : Colored; 58 cm. x 97 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "This is a popular map of Africa and has been reissued many time with variations..." Dedication: 'To the T. Honourable Charles Earl of Peterborow and Monmouth.' Inset: A prospect of the Cape of Good Hope, Cape Coast Castle, Guinea. James Fort, St. Helena, Fort of Good Hope; Prime meridian through London and Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0067, p. 81
  Norwich number: 0067
  RID: MOA 0281
- Representatio Totius Africae ... = Representing the whole of Africa ... -- Munich: Scherer, Heinrich, 1628-1704; Scherer, Heinrich, 1628-1704, 1710; NOR 0068; : Uncolored; 22 cm. x 34 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Similar but less detailed than Scherer's map (see NOR 0062). An angel carrying a scroll with an extract from the Bible. Below the angel are five figures in native African and oriental dress. In the opposite corner are four figures kneeling and praying.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0068, p. 83
  Norwich number: 0068
  RID: MOA 0123
- Africa Corrected from the Observations of the Royal Society of London and Paris. -- London: Senex, J. (John), d. 1740; Senex, J. (John), d. 1740, 1711-1714; NOR 0069; : Colored; 69 cm. x 97 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Similar cartouche to Price's map of 1711, see NOR 0077. Shape of continent is fairly accurate, though fictitious place exist on the mainland; Prime meridian though London. Dedicated to Sir Issac Newton.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0069, p. 84
  Norwich number: 0069
  RID: MOA 0308
- L'Afrique selon les nouvelles observations de Messieurs de l'Academie de Sciences etc. = Africa according to the latest observations made by the Academy of Science. -- Leiden: Aa, Pieter van der, 1659-1733 (1713 edition); Aa, Pieter van der, 1659-1733, NOR 0070; : Colored; 47 cm. x 65 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Reissued in 1729. Cartouche includes a nude woman sitting on a rectangle of masonry located in a rural scene with elephants, a lion and a snake. Legend states, "I would rather show this part of Africa as unknown and unihabited than rely on my imagination." Title across top, Africa in praecipuas ipsius partes distributa ...
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0070, p. 85
  Norwich number: 0070
  RID: MOA 0151
- Africa Antiqua et Nova. = Africa ancient and modern. -- London: Moll, Herman, d. 1732; Moll, Herman, d. 1732, 1714; NOR 0071; : Colored; 21 cm. x 26 cm.
  Source: Atlas Geographus: or a Complete System of Georgraphy (1714)
  Descriptive Notes: "Map has the usual features of eighteenth-century maps, particularly in its large lakes and rivers." Top right: pag. 623.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0071, p. 86
  Norwich number: 0071
  RID: MOA 0180
- Totius Africa Nova Repraesentatio qua practer diversos in ea Status et Regiones, etiam Origo Nili et veris RRPP Missionariorum Relationibus ostenditur ... = The whole of Africa divided into states and regions ... -- Nurnberg: Homann, Johann Baptist, 1663-1724; Homann, Johann Baptist, 1663-1724, 1715; NOR 0072; : Colored; 47 cm. x 56 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Cartouche provides an elaborate scene depicting natives on the Nile bank. Nearby are monkeys, a sheep and a tortoise. Cherubs floating above complete the picture. Even though the map includes a note declaring the accuracy for the source of the Nile, it proves to be inaccurate; Prime meridian through Tenerif.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0072, p. 87
  Norwich number: 0072
  RID: MOA 0256
- Nouvelle Carte d'Afrique avec des remarques et des tables pour trouver sans peine les differents peuples de cette partie du monde par les renvois alphabetiques suivant les plus nouvelles observations de messieurs de l'Academie des siences. = New map of Africa with observations and index ... -- Amsterdam Chatelain, Henri Abraham, 1718; NOR 0073; : Colored; 46 cm. x 58 cm.
  Source: Atlas Historique (1718)
  Descriptive Notes: Collaborative effort by Chatelain and Guedeville. Map is based on the 1700 edition of de L'Isle's map (see NOR 0059). Inset shows alphabetical index of kingdoms, provinces, towns, islands, capes, rivers and lakes. Top right: No. D; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0073, p. 88
  Norwich number: 0073
  RID: MOA 0120
- L'Afrique Dressee sur les Observations de Ms. de l'Academie Royale des Sciences et quelques autres sur les Memoires les plus recens. = Africa according to the observations made by the Royal Academy of Science. -- Amsterdam: Covens, Jean; Mortier, Corneille; L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726, 1730; NOR 0074; : Colored; 46 cm. x 57 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Retains the geographical features of L'Isle's map of 1700 (see NOR 0059). Title across top: Africa Accurate in Imperia, Regna, Status and Populos Divisa, ad Usum Serenissimi Bourgundiae Ducis. Dedicated to the Duke to Burgundy; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0074, p. 89
  Norwich number: 0074
  RID: MOA 0225
- Africa Mauro Percussa Oceano, Niloque admota tepenti ... Cum Privilegio Ordinum Hollandia et Westfrisia. -- Amsterdam: Valck, G. (Gerard), 1651 or 2-1726; Valk, Leonard, 1675-1755; Valck, G. (Gerard), 1651 or 2-1726; Valk, Leonard, 1675-1755, circa 1720; NOR 0075; : Colored; 49 cm. x 59 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Typical features of eighteenth-century Dutch maps of Africa; Prime meridian through Tenerif.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map. 0075, p. 90
  Norwich number: 0075
  RID: MOA 0214
- A New map of Africa from the latest observations. -- London: Senex, J. (John), d. 1740; Senex, J. (John), d. 1740, 1721; NOR 0076; : Outline color; 48 cm. x 55 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The cartouche includes a shield, which is surrounded by a dragon, two pyramids, two male figures, a lion and a snake. Dedicated to the Marquis of Annandale; Prime meridian through London.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0076, p. 91
  Norwich number: 0076
  RID: MOA 0211
- Africa corrected from observations of Mess. of ye Royal Societies at London and Paris. -- London: Price, Charles, fl. 1680-1720; Price, Charles, fl. 1680-1720, 1721; NOR 0077; : Colored; 56 cm. x 95 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Parts of the cartouche appear in other maps. Left side of the cartouche is similar to Pieter van der Aa's map, see NOR 0070. While the figure on the right side is identical to Senex's map, see NOR 0069. Inset: Instruments used in map making. Scenes of cannibalism.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0077, p. 92
  Norwich number: 0077
  RID: MOA 0287
- Carte D'Afrique Dressee pour l'usage du Roy ... = Map of Africa for the King ... -- Amsterdam: Covens, Jean; Mortier, Corneille; L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726; L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726, 1722; NOR 0078; : Colored; 48 cm. x 62 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "... one of the series of revised maps that L'Isle's first issued in 1722". Title across top: Africa Accurate in Imperia, Regna Status e Populus Divisa ad Usum Lodovici XV Galliarum Regis; Prime meridian through Ferro Island and Paris. Dedicated to Louis XV.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0078, p. 93
  Norwich number: 0078
  RID: MOA 0302
- To Her Most Sacred Majesty Caroline, Queen of Great Britain, France and Ireland this Mapp of Africa, after the latest and best Observations is most humbly dedicated ... -- London: Overton, Henry, fl. 1706-1764; Overton, John, 1640-1708?, circa 1727; NOR 0079; : Colored; 57 cm. x 97 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Borders illustrate thirteen scenes of African life and African forts.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0079, p. 94
  Norwich number: 0079
  RID: MOA 0286
- Africa Juxta Navigationes et Observationes Recentissimas Aucta, Correcta et in Sua Regna et Status Divisa in Lucem Edita ... = Africa according to the latest voyages and observations. -- Vienna: Seutter, Matthaeus, 1678-1756; Seutter, Matthaeus, 1678-1756; Seutter, Matthaeus, 1678-1756, 1728; NOR 0080; : Uncolored; 49 cm. x 57 cm.
  Source: Atlas Novus (1728)
  Descriptive Notes: Cartouche includes natives, pyramids, animals, lighthouses and ships. "Enormous lakes are shown in Central Africa and the information about the southern extremity of the continent is largely fictitious."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0080, p. 0095
  Norwich number: 0080
  RID: MOA 0212
- Old Map of the Continent according to the greatest diametrical Length from the Point of East Tartary to the Cape of Good Hope. -- London: Jefferys, Thomas, d. 1771; Gibson, J. (John); Gibson, J. (John), 1731; NOR 0081; : Uncolored; 21.5 cm. x 18 cm.
  Source: Gentleman's Magazine or Monthly Intelligence, vol. 1, 1731. London, F. Jeffery.
  Descriptive Notes: Map includes Europe, Asia and the Far East. The oval-shaped cartouche contains a floral border with a female face wearing a wide-brimmed hat.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0081, p. 96
  Norwich number: 0081
  RID: MOA 0030
  Africa -- Africa, Europe and Asia -- 18th c.
- Carte Generale de L'Afrique Contenant les Principaux Etats qui y sont Contenue Dressee sur les Nouvelles Observations. = General map of Africa showing the principal states according to the latest observations. -- Paris: Crepy, Jean, 1660-ca. 1730; Inslin, Charles (fl. 1699-1735), NOR 0082; : Outline color; 51 cm. x 64 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Twenty-nine coasts of arms, representing the major cities of Europe, surround the cartouche. Prime meridian through Ferro Island and Paris.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0082, p. 97
  Norwich number: 0082
  RID: MOA 0304
- Africa Secundum legitimas Projectionis Stereographicae regulas et juxta recentissimas relationes et observationes in subsidium vocatis quoque veterum Leonis Africani Nubiensis Geographi et aliorum monumentis et eleminatis fabulosis aliorum designationibus pro praesenti statu ejus aptius exhibita. = Africa according to the most recent reports and observations. -- Nuremberg: Homann Heirs; Hase, Johann Matthias, 1684-1742, 1737?; NOR 0083; : Colored; 45 cm. x 54 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The title consists of a panel surrounded by elephant's tusks resting on a piece of masonry. On the left are four Africans and on the right an interview between Europeans and Africans. The African chief is sitting on the back on another who is crouching on a mat; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0083, p. 98
  Norwich number: 0083
  RID: MOA 0231
- Carta Generale Dell' Africa. = General map of Africa. -- Italy L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726, 1740-1750; NOR 0084; : Uncolored; 33 cm. x 42 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Italian edition. The cartouche illustrates a youth spearing a crocodile, another person riding a horse, nearby an elephant and a ostrich. An accurate geographical outline of the continent.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0084, p. 100
  Norwich number: 0084
  RID: MOA 0031
- Afrique selon les Relations les plus Nouvelles Dressee sur les Memoires du ... Divisee en tousses Royaumes et grands Etats avec un discours sur la nouvelle decouverte de la situation des sources du Nil. = Africa according to recent findings ... with a note about the latest discovery regarding the sources of regarding the sources of the Nile. -- Paris: J. B. Nolin; Du Tralage, Jean Nicolas, d. 1699; Nolin, Jean Baptiste, 1686-1762, 1742; NOR 0085; : Colored; 45 cm. x 58 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0085, p. 101
  Norwich number: 0085
  RID: MOA 0235
- L'Afrique Suivant les Derniers Observations de Mr. Hass et des RRPP Jesuites. = Africa according to recent observations made by Mr. Hass and the Jesuits. -- Paris: Le Rouge, Georges-Louis; Le Rouge, Georges-Louis, 1747; NOR 0087; : Outline color; 49 cm. x 63 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Similar title cartouche to Homann's map, see NOR 0083. Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0087, p. 103
  Norwich number: 0087
  RID: MOA 0280
- Lacs, Fleuves, Rivieres et Principales Montagnes de L'Afrique. = Lakes, rivers and principal mountains of Africa. -- Paris: Clouet, Jean Baptiste Louis, 1730-; Clouet, Jean Baptiste Louis, 1730-, No date; NOR 0088; : Outline color; 41 cm. x 39 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Includes French text in margins. An accurate outline of the continent with minimum geographical detail. Similar features to d'Anville's map of 1727 (see NOR 0091); Prime meridian through Ferro Island. Top right corner: No. 14. Top left corner: Introduction.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0088, p. 104
  Norwich number: 0088
  RID: MOA 0192
- Lacs, Fleuves, Rivieres et Principales Montagnes de L'Afrique. = Lakes, rivers and principal mountains of Africa. -- Paris: Clouet, Jean Baptiste Louis, 1730-; Clouet, Jean Baptiste Louis, 1730-, No date; NOR 0088a; : Outline color; 41 cm. x 39 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Duplicate map. Includes French text in margins. An accurate outline of the continent with minimum geographical detail. Similar features to d'Anville's map of 1727 (see NOR 0091); Prime meridian through Ferro Island. Top right corner: No. 14. Top left corner: Introduction.
  Norwich number: 0088a
  RID: MOA 0257
- A new and correct map of Africa. Drawn from the most approved modern maps and charts, and adjusted by astronomical observations representing also the course of the Trade Winds, Monsoons c. -- London: Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767; Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767, 1748; NOR 0089; : Uncolored; 37 cm. x 45 cm.
  Source: Collection of Voyages (1748)
  Descriptive Notes: Ilustrates the various winds, and is almost free of decoration except for the cartouche. Gold and silver mines appear in Zimbabwe. Top right: Vol. 1. Page 717; Prime meridian through London.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0089, p. 105
  Norwich number: 0089
  RID: MOA 0106
- L'Afrique divisee en ses principales parties. = Africa divided into its principal parts. -- Paris: Robert de Vaugondy, the family of; Robert de Vaugondy, the family of; Robert de Vaugondy, the family of, 1748; NOR 0090; : Colored; 15.5 cm. x 19.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Top right: 171.